《哥谭》上季提要
Last season on Gotham...
就在这里  就在这间屋子里
It's in here. It's in this room.
我父亲的秘密  就在这间屋子里
My father's secret, it's in this room.
你要查洛布那就是自杀  没其他可能
Going after Loeb is suicide, plain and simple.
你又在错误的时间出现在错误的地点
As usual, wrong place, wrong time.
你真是个耻辱  洛布
You're a disgrace, Loeb.
黑的白的一身红  是什么  别说那种话
What's black and white and red all over? Stop talking like that.
你为什么杀你母亲  杰罗姆
Why did you kill your mother, Jerome?
芭芭拉  杰森·列侬杀了你父母
Barbara, Jason Lennon killed your parents.
-不是你杀了他们  -是我啊
- You didn't kill them. - Yes, I did.
再见了  菲什
Good-bye, Fish.
我是哥谭之王
I'm the king of Gotham!
你觉得这是什么
What is it, do you think?
翻译 DustD   蓬蓬裙   艾瑞卡   Silence   木浅   辰星晓Reginamoon
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 夜影章鱼X   校对 夜影章鱼X   草草   时间轴 凭陵新月
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   后期 宝宝   总监 草草
我的天啊
Bloody hell.
别  等等  等等
No, wait, wait, wait!
拒绝进入
密码有数百万种可能  布鲁斯少爷
There must be a million possible combinations, Master Bruce.
拒绝进入
一个月后
*真是完美的一天*
*Just a perfect day*
*在公园里小酌桑格利亚*
*Drink sangria in the park*
*然后过一会儿*
*And then later*
*天黑了我们就回家*
*when it gets dark we go home*
*真是完美的一天*
*Just a perfect day*
*在动物园里喂动物*
*Feed animals in the zoo*
*过一会儿*
*Then later*
*再看场电影  最后回家*
*a movie, too. And then home*
*这真是完美的一天*
*Oh, it's such a perfect day*
*很高兴与你一起度过*
*I'm glad I spent it with you*
*这真是完美的一天*
*Oh, such a perfect day*
*你让我流连忘返*
*You just keep me hanging on*
都喝掉
Drink it all.
谢谢你  主人
Thank you, Master.
现在去吧
Now go.
走吧  赶紧  赶紧
Come on through. Let's go, let's go.
-我是扎丹  -闭嘴吧
- I am Zaardon... - Shut up!
灵魂收割者
The Soul Reaper!
愚蠢的奴隶  你们无法逃脱我的掌心
Foolish slaves! You cannot escape me!
先生  放下你的枪
Sir, drop the guns!
你  你
You! You!
过来
Come on...!
你原始的武器无法伤我丝毫
Your primitive weapons cannot hurt me!
准备受死吧  虫子
Prepare to die, insect.
听着  我不想冲你开枪  好吗
Listen, I don't want to shoot you, man, all right?
写报告太麻烦了
Too much paperwork.
所以咱就  把剑放下吧
So why don't you just... put the sword down.
别动  放松
Stay down. Relax.
戈登
Yo, Gordon.
-怎么了  挺忙啊  -你迟到了
- What's up? Busy shift? - You're late.
天啊  放松点行吗  你这人怎么回事
Geez, relax, will ya? What's the matter with you, man?
别这么做
Bad idea.
这怎么可能
How can this be?
扎丹喝了主人圣杯中的龙之血
Zaardon drank dragon's blood from the master's Chalice.
"渣蛋"  这么写对吗
"Zar-don"... that spelled how it sounds?
-是扎丹  -够接近了
- Two A's. - Close enough.
你胆敢送我进监狱
You dare send me to prison?
不会  你肯定是进阿卡姆的料
Oh, no... you're a cinch for Arkham.
你给我听着  戈蛋
Hear me, Gor-Don.
你也许赢下了这场战斗
You might have won this battle,
但是战争才刚刚开始
but the war has just begun.
主人会让你痛不欲生的
The master will unleash hell upon you.
黑暗之日即将来临
Dark days are coming.
谢谢提醒
Thanks for the heads-up.
爱德
Ed.
你没事吧
You okay?
再好不过了
Never better.
戈登警官23611
Officer Gordon 23611,
请立刻来警监办公室报到
report to the captain's office immediately.
叫我了
I'm up.
回头见
See ya.
他走了  放轻松
He's gone. Relax.
哎呀妈呀  看看你
Holy moly, look at you!
大家都会认为你要疯了
Everyone's gonna think you're going nuts.
刚才那样有人在的时候
I get nervous when you talk to me
你和我说话会让我紧张
with other people around like that.
别再那样了
Stop doing that.
-哪样  -那样
- What? - That!
学我的样子
Copying me.
伙计  这是镜子  镜子就这样
Dude... it's a mirror, that's how they work.
知道我们需要什么吗
You know what I think we need?
我觉得我们需要...
I think that we need...
找点乐子
a little more fun.
来点浪漫
Some romance.
住口  我知道你要说什么
Stop. I know where this is going.
我早说了  别把柯林格小姐扯进来
I told you, leave... Miss Kringle alone.
想想她依偎在我们的臂弯里
Imagine her in our arms.
那双大眼睛望着我们
Those big eyes looking up at us,
她柔软  颤栗的身体
and soft, trembling flesh.
闭嘴
Be quiet!
这问题很简单  戈登警官
It's a simple question, Officer Gordon...
你有没有碰弗兰克斯警官
did you or did you not put your hands on Officer Franks here?
我碰了
Yes. I did.
从上岗的第一天开始
From the first day on the job,
你就是个不听话的刺头
you've been an insubordinate troublemaker.
我本以为降职你去执勤能让你知难而退
I hoped demotion to uniform duty would suffice to make you quit.
你的搭档布洛克就挺懂事
It worked for your partner, Bullock.
而你亲口承认违反了第12条规定
However, you've now confessed to violation of section 12.
因此你立刻离职  强制执行
Immediate dismissal is mandatory.
局长  这不公平
Commissioner, this is not just.
弗兰克斯警官没有受伤
Officer Franks sustained no harm,
而戈登警官在制服一个凶恶歹徒的过程中
and Officer Gordon showed admirable restraint
已经显示了很大的克制
in defusing a dangerous hostage situation.
谢谢你的提醒  警监
Thank you so much for your input, Captain.
事实就是事实
The facts speak for themselves.
事实证明  他应该得到赞扬
The facts say he deserves commendation,
而不是被离职
not dismissal.
你这是让龌龊政治...
You're letting gutter politics...
够了  小姑娘
That's enough, young lady.
请把戈登警官...
Take Officer...
戈登先生的警徽和枪收回  这是命令
Mister Gordon's badge and gun. That's an order.
好吧  算了
All good. Let it go.
还是谢谢你
Thanks, though.
和您共事是我的荣幸
It's been an honor working for you.
这样也好
This is all for the best, you know.
有些人就不适合当警察
Some men are just not meant to be cops.
我说过  我会战胜你的
I told you I'd break you.
一定会的
I will.
哥谭
第二季  第一集
你对洛布说什么了  你发火了吗
What did you say to Loeb? Did you get mad?
我不认同他的决定
Well, I disagreed with his decision.
别这样  你知道我要刨根问底的
Come on. You know I need the details.
我说我会战胜他的
I said I'd break him.
就那个意思
Words to that effect.
临走也要留句狠话
You went out with a bang.
也许这样也好
Maybe it's for the best.
洛布也这么说
That's what Loeb said.
我本该一走了之  但我不想放弃[辞职]
I should have walked away. I just hate to quit.
你没有辞职
You didn't quit.
你是被炒了  还能怎么办
You were fired. What can you do?
我还有办法
Oh, there's things I can do.
你不是说  你已经没有合法的手段了吗
I thought you said you didn't have any legal moves left.
是啊
I don't.
你就那么想当警察  不惜犯法吗
You want to be a cop so bad, you're willing to break the law?
我愿意做一点妥协
I'm willing to bend it a little, yeah.
我被炒了你很高兴吧
You're happy I got fired, huh?
被你看穿了
You got me.
因为我知道  你永远不会辞职的
But only because I know that you'll never quit.
我也因此爱你
And I love that about you.
但他们都让你去指挥交通了  吉姆
But they have you directing traffic, Jim.
为什么要不停地撞南墙呢
Why keep beating your head against a wall.
我是个警察  小莱
I'm a cop, Lee.
我是个警察
I'm a cop.
好啊美人  我叫杰罗姆
Hi, gorgeous. I'm Jerome.
别烦我  小红毛
Keep moving, ginger.
就是客气一下嘛  你怎么进来的
Just being polite. So, what-cha in for?
杀了我爸妈
Killing my parents.
我也是
Me, too.
其实只杀了我妈
Well... Mom, anyhow.
很舒爽  是吧
What a liberating, right?
很刺激
what a rush!
好吧好吧
Yeah, all righty, then.
看见那个大块头帅哥
You see the big handsome fella
一直盯着你  好像你是砧上肉似的吗
staring at you like you're fried chicken?
理查德·西恩尼斯  他是百万富翁
Richard Sionis. He's a millionaire.
有私人飞机  有带热浴缸的私人游艇
Got his own airplane. Got a boat with a hot tub on it.
他杀了25个人  就为了好玩
And he killed 25 people... just for fun.
那又怎样
So what?
他喜欢你
So... he likes you.
他想当你朋友
He wants to be your friend.
容我考虑一下  没门
Let me think. No.
女生在这里得有个靠谱的朋友
A girl needs a good friend in here.
那些警卫  他们才不在乎
See, the guards, they don't care.
他们觉得坏人都是罪有应得
They figure bad things happen to bad people.
坏事常有发生
And they happen all the time.
常有发生
All the time.
你
You.
叫你呢  光头仔
Hello? Baldy!
这呢  这呢  就是你  过来
Here, here. Hello, yes. Hi. Come here.
我叫芭芭拉
My name is Barbara.
-愿意和我做朋友吗  -当然
- Would you be my friend? - Yes.
要是这里有人想伤害我
If someone here tries to hurt me...
-你会保护我吗  -当然会啊
- would you protect me? - Yes.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
真帅
Cutie.
现在我有朋友了
Now I have a friend.
你真坏
You're bad.
是啊  帮我做个三明治去吧
Yeah, so why don't you go make me a sandwich.
你朋友是个大猩猩  我的朋友是这里的老大
Your friend is a gorilla. My friend runs the joint.
他能给你别人给不了你的东西
And he can get you things that other people can't get you.
例如说
Things like what?
你需要的任何东西
Anything you need.
我需要电话
I need a telephone.
奥格登·巴克  欠了七万
Ogden Barker, in for 70 grand,
再加两个月的保护费  250多
plus two months vig, 250 and change.
说他欠的是法尔科内
Says he owes Falcone.
法尔科内一走  他的债也两清了
Falcone's gone, so his debt's forfeit.
可不能让他说这种话
Well, we can't have him saying that.
要是大家都开始这么说怎么办
What if everybody started saying that?
那就乱套了
There'd be anarchy.
怎么了
What is it?
棒极了
Splendid.
吉姆  来啊
Jim! Come on in!
-我亲爱的老朋友  -我们得谈谈
- My dear old friend. - We need to talk.
让我们单独待会儿
Leave us.
塞琳娜  更上一层了啊
Selina. Moving on up, huh?
-在努力呢  -她是不是很可爱
- Tryin. - Isn't she darling?
就像是家里养了只猫
It's like having a cat around the house.
又不会有讨厌的死老鼠
But no horrid dead mice.
我要你帮个忙  我觉得你欠我的
I need a favor. I figure you owe me one.
是吗
I do?
我一向乐意帮你  吉姆  但我不记得
I'm always happy to help you, Jim, but I-I, I don't recall...
医院那事  我从马罗尼的人手底下救了你
The hospital. I saved you from Maroni's men.
但我当时在那儿也是因为你逮捕了我
But I was only there because you arrested me.
因为你谋杀未遂
For attempted murder.
我为什么放你走来着
Remind me again why I let you go.
因为友谊万岁
Enlightened friendship.
要我说我们扯平了
I'd call us even, but...
但咱就别纠结了
let's not quibble.
我很高兴你来找我帮忙  吉姆
I'm so happy you came to me for help, Jim.
答案是可以  你的愿望会实现的
The answer is yes. Your wish is granted.
你还不知道我要你帮什么
You don't know what it is yet.
你想让洛布下台  好恢复原职  不是吗
You want Loeb fired, and your old job back, no?
没错
Yes.
为你这样的好朋友  这事没问题
For a good friend like you, it can be done.
只要你确定这是你想要的
If you're sure that's what you want.
我确定
I'm sure.
我能问问原因吗
May I ask why?
哥谭的警察一向出力不讨好
Police work in Gotham is such a thankless job.
养老金不错
Good pension.
小莱怎么看
What does Lee think?
谁
Who?
你到底帮不帮我
Are you gonna help me or not?
放松  我不都答应了吗
Relax. I already said I would help.
他可真没礼貌  不是吗
He is so brusque, isn't he?
不  谢谢你
No, thank you.
我又想了想
While I think on it,
也许你能帮我个小忙
perhaps there's a small favor you could do for me in return.
我知道你有多讨厌欠人情债
I know how you hate to owe favors.
我和一个朋友目前在生意上有些小纠纷
I am having a small business dispute with a friend of mine.
他叫奥格登·巴克
Ogden Barker.
你很有说服力
You have a persuasive personality.
也许你可以和他谈谈
Perhaps you could talk to him.
你要我帮你收账吗
You want me to collect a debt for you?
我要你向我证明我们的友情是真的
I want you to prove to me that our friendship is a real one,
是以信任和公平为基础的
based on trust and equity.
很公平
That's fair.
不行  抱歉  帮不了你
No. Sorry. Can't help you.
恭喜你取得的成功
Congratulations on all your success.
乖乖的  塞琳娜
Be good, Selina.
一向如此
Always.
别这么快拒绝我  吉姆  考虑一晚
Don't say no now, Jim. Sleep on it.
去他的企鹅
Screw Penguin,
去他的哥谭市警局
screw the GCPD,
让这座城市见鬼去吧
and screw this city.
阿门  你做得没错  兄弟
Amen. You're doing the right thing, brother.
别管了  吉姆  放手吧
Walk away, Jim, just walk away.
换做是你也会这样做吧
You'd do the same thing, right?
我  我愿给恶魔端三明治  但那只是我
Me? I'd serve a sandwich to Beelzebub, but that's just me.
你是个品行端正的人
You are a moralist.
你绝不可能帮企鹅做事
You could never work for Penguin.
那种耻辱会吞噬你的意志
The shame would eat away at your guts.
是啊
Yeah...
没错
Yeah.
慢点喝  别着急
Slow down, slurpy.
你不跟我一起喝吗
You're not joining me?
我已经32天没喝酒了
I've been sober 32 days.
32天
32 days, huh?
没什么大不了的
It's no biggie.
一把工作辞了  戒酒就容易了
Once I quit the job, quitting drinking was easy.
是因为那份工作  吉姆
It's the job, Jim.
让我们生气  让我们冷酷
Makes us angry. Makes us hard.
的确是
Yeah, it does.
很难抽离  但还是能做到的
It's hard to walk away, but it can be done.
我就是无法再扛着那枚警徽了
I just couldn't carry that badge anymore.
瞧瞧我现在  我戒了酒
Look at me now. Right? I'm sober...
我身边有个不嫌弃我的女人
I have a woman who does not dislike me,
有瓦遮头  夜里睡得安心
I live in a house, I sleep at night.
我的生活从未如此开心过
I've never been happier in my life.
为平民生活干杯
Here's to civilian life.
我为你骄傲  兄弟
I'm proud of you, brother.
走了
Got to go.
真的非常抱歉
I really am most frightfully sorry
这么久才开门  先生
it took so long to answer the door, sir.
真奇怪
Strange.
通常一有车经过大门  警报器就会响
Normally a buzzer sounds when a car comes through the gates.
我走路来的
I walked.
你们俩怎么脏兮兮的  在干什么呢
You two are dirty. What have you been doing?
我想你有重要的事要说
I imagine you have something important to say.
没错
Yes.
我被哥谭市警局开除了
I've been fired from the GCPD.
我无法履行对你的承诺了
I won't be able to keep the promise I made you.
我想和你道歉
I wanted to apologize.
我当然接受你的道歉  可是
Your apology's accepted, of course, but...
你不必大老远走一趟
you didn't need to walk here.
打电话过来就行了
A phone call would've been fine.
我想呼吸下新鲜空气
I needed the air.
复职无望喽  先生
No hope for reinstatement then, sir?
是啊
No.
还有个办法  可是
Well, there is a way, but...
太不光明磊落
it's too ugly.
我得帮企鹅收账
I would have to collect a debt for Penguin.
以此证明我们的友情
To prove our friendship.
你不能这么做  因为
And you can't do that, because...
他不是个好人
he's a bad man.
而且向人收账有辱你的人格
And the task would be demeaning.
没错
Well, yes.
你本打算查明杀害我父母的凶手
You were going to find my parents' killers.
为正义而战
You were going to fight for justice.
整顿哥谭市警局
You were going to clean up the GCPD.
-改变哥谭  -我本是希望那么做
- Change Gotham. - I had hoped to do that.
如果你留在哥谭市警局
If you remained at the GCPD,
你也许还能做这些好事  但是
you might still be able to do all those good things, but first...
你得先做些见不得光的事
you must do something ugly.
而你的个人荣誉感不允许你这么做
And your personal honor forbids that.
是的
Yes.
你这不是为你个人的尊严与体面
Are you not sacrificing the greater good
而选择了牺牲大局吗
for the sake of your dignity and self-esteem?
-这不是虚荣吗  -别乱说  布鲁斯少爷
- For vanity? - Steady on, now, Master Bruce.
要有礼貌
Manners.
他走了这么远来探讨这个问题  阿尔弗雷德
He walked all the way here to discuss the issue, Alfred.
我只是问个问题
I'm simply asking a question.
有时候  正确的路
Surely, sometimes, the right way
不也是肮脏的路吗
is also the ugly way.
有时候人没法选择正确的路
Sometimes a man can't take the right way.
他现在要处理许多
He's dealing with all kinds of business
你还无法理解的事
you can't possibly understand yet,
因为你还是个孩子
because you're still a child.
是啊  阿尔弗雷德
Yes, Alfred,
确实还有很多事我无法理解
there is still a great deal I don't understand yet.
如果冒犯了你请原谅  吉姆
Please forgive me if I've offended you, Jim.
没有  没关系
No, no. That's okay.
我送你出去  先生
I'll show you out, sir.
拒绝进入
去他的吧
Screw it.
阿卡姆疯人院
杰罗姆说你能弄到电话
Jerome says you can get me a telephone.
我乐意帮助朋友
I try and help my friends.
那你要朋友怎么回报呢
What do your friends do for you?
这要看  你有多么
Well, that depends... on how much...
想要
you want...
用电话
a telephone.
给我站住
Hold it right there.
奥格登·巴克
Ogden Barker.
企鹅让我来找你谈
Penguin asked me to talk to you.
天哪  真是
Damn, boy.
你刚进来还吓我一跳
You had me worried there for a minute.
我知道你  你是吉姆·戈登
I know you. You're Jim Gordon.
警察  据说很厉害很冷血
Cop. Supposed to be a cold stone hard-ass.
但你现在跟着企鹅混了吗
But you're Penguin's bitch, huh?
这世道真是人心不古了啊
Who the dickens can you trust anymore?
他要你交钱
He wants his money.
我得跟你们说多少次  我不交
How many times I got to tell you people? No.
给法尔科内阁下  我愿意交
To Don Falcone, I'll pay.
给那个疯子小怪物
To that fruitcake leprechaun?
绝不
Nish.
-一个子儿都不给  -法尔科内退位了
- Not a penny. - Falcone's retired.
世道变了
Times change.
现在企鹅是老大
Penguin's boss now.
得了吧
Like hell.
那个怪物一年都撑不下来
The freak won't last the year.
别小看他
Don't underestimate him.
-还提建议了啊  -我是先礼后兵
- Advice now. - I'm trying to be nice here.
我们商量个解决办法吧
Let's work this out.
是吗  还是别商量了吧
Yeah? Let's not.
走吧
Walk away.
Walk away...
免得我揍你  你个混混
before I kick your ass, you crooked punk bitch.
你这一堆有多少钱
How much money you got there?
看起来不少啊
Looks like a lot.
你有病啊
What is your problem?
我没病  把你欠的钱还了
I don't have a problem. Give me the money you owe.
不如我在你脸上开个洞吧
How about I put a hole in your face?
我数到三
I'm gonna count to three.
你真是疯了
You're crazy.
一
One...
把钱放到袋子里  快点
Put the money in the bag. Do it!
给我把他抓住
Oh-ho-ho, get him, man.
站住  小偷
Stop! Thief!
让开
Out of the way.
警察
Hey, cop...
化肥  你要干什么啊
Fertilizer? What is your game?
我以为你这么敏锐的人肯定能看出来呢
I would've thought that's obvious to a man of your perception.
我决定采纳自己的建议
It occurred to me to follow my own advice.
有时候肮脏的路也是正确的路
Sometimes the ugly way is also the right way.
不是吧  做炸弹  就在房子里
I mean, a bomb, inside the house?
你是开玩笑呢吧  做炸弹
I mean, you're having a laugh, ain't ya? A bomb?
我本来想告诉你的
I was going to tell you.
我想等它成了既成事实再说
I wanted to present it as a fait accompli.
别跟我用法语
Don't start talking French to me.
你根本不懂如何做炸弹吧  是不是
You don't know the first thing about bomb-making anyway, do you?
我读过一本书  阿尔弗雷德
I read a book, Alfred...
看起来挺简单的
it seems simple enough.
一本书
A book.
你没把门怎么样
I mean, you're gonna blow your bloody head off
就会先把自己的头炸飞
before you put a dent in that thing.
也许那扇门是向我们预示了什么
You know, maybe that door's trying to tell us something.
也许你还没准备好  了解门后的真相
Maybe you're not ready to find out what's behind it.
也许我们该等你再大一些
Maybe we should wait until you're older.
谁知道你亲爱的老爹
I mean, who knows what your dear old dad
在那底下搞了什么东西
was up to down there, anyway.
比如说
Like what?
比如说我不愿向一个孩子描述的东西
Like things I wouldn't want... to describe to a child,
而你也就是个孩子
which is exactly what you are.
我要做炸弹炸掉那扇门
I'm building a bomb to blow down that door.
你可以帮我...
You may assist me...
或者不帮  随你的便
or not, as you wish.
但假如不帮  就给我泡杯茶吧
But I-if not, some tea would be nice.
好吧  你首先还需要...
Right, well, you're gonna need ten more
再找十袋那玩意
sacks of that gear, for starters;
还要再找三个牛奶罐
three more dairy cans, too;
再多找些木料  以及...
and extra timber and a...
一块厚防水布
heavy tarpaulin.
我去给您烧水泡茶
And I'll put the kettle on.
棒极了
Excellent.
棒极了  很抱歉事情闹得那么大
Excellent. I'm so sorry things got messy.
真是个傻瓜
What a foolish fellow.
没事  我会保证你的同事
Never mind. I will make sure that there's
不会继续追查此事
no follow-up from your colleagues.
-别担心  -你早知道
- Don't worry about a thing. - You knew.
你早知道奥格登会反抗的
You knew Ogden would go off.
你想太多了
What a devious mind you have.
我怎么知道
I had no idea.
我们约好了的
We have a deal.
是的  没错
We do. We do.
你没事吧  吉姆
You okay, Jim?
没事  走神而已
Oh, yeah. Daydreaming.
怎么了
What's wrong?
没事
Nothing.
喂
Hello.
喂  吉姆吗
Hello? Jim?
喂  你还在听吗
Hello? Are you still there?
在
I'm here.
你好吗
How are you?
你怎么拿到电话的
How did you get to a phone?
谁在乎这个
Who cares?
我们终于通上话了...这才是重要的
We're talking at last... that's the important thing.
你想要什么
What do you want?
吉姆  他们搞错了
Jim, there's been a terrible mistake.
我...从没跟小莱说
I... never told Lee
我杀了我爸和我妈
that I killed my mom and dad.
而且我也没攻击她
And I never attacked her.
是她攻击了我  吉姆
She attacked me, Jim.
她完全疯了
She's completely insane!
够了  别再打电话过来了
That's enough. Don't call again.
谁打来的
Who was that?
推销的
Sales call.
他们真能把人逼疯  是吧
They can drive you crazy, huh?
推销的
Sales call?
别
Don't.
怎么了
What?
别接电话
Don't answer it.
吉姆  你吓到我了
Jim, you're scaring me.
是芭芭拉
It's Barbara.
请留言
Go ahead and leave a message.
好啊  妹子
Hey, girlfriend.
猜猜是谁
Guess who.
真可惜你不在  遗憾啊
Sorry I missed you. Bummer, eh?
我只是想说
I just wanted to say
希望你惨叫着死去  婊子
that I hope you die screaming, bitch.
再见
Bye.
真棒
Nice.
好吧  听着...
All right, look...
她妥妥地关在阿卡姆呢  她伤害不了你
she's safely locked up at Arkham. She can't hurt you.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
她只是个传播负能量的疯子
She's just a sick person spreading sadness.
去她的
Screw her.
我们好好过  我们一起离开吧
Let's be happy. Let's go away someplace.
我们不能让个疯女人把我们逼走
We can't let a crazy woman drive us out.
为什么  要面子吗  谁在乎
Why not? Pride? Who cares?
我们可以远走高飞  再也不回来
We could go away and never come back.
这里有什么可留恋的
What's keeping us here?
我不能走
I can't leave.
为什么不能
Why not?
吉姆
Jim...
我做了件坏事
I did a bad thing.
你这里有花生酱吗
Do you have any peanut butter?
什么
What?!
花生酱  丝滑花生酱最好
Peanut butter. Smooth, for preference.
警卫  快来  救命
Guards, help! Help!
你好啊老大
Oh, hi, boss.
喝杯啤酒吗
How about a bottle of beer?
我有个难处跟你说说
Let me share a dilemma with you.
你不介意吧
May I?
我想让你帮我做件事
I need you to do something for me
可我又知道你不会乐意的
that I know you won't want to do.
什么事
What is it?
一般人都好对付
With most people, there's no problem.
我找出他们的弱点  用暴力
I find their weak spots and use violence
或者敲诈让他们低头
or blackmail to persuade them.
但是你
But you...
你干净得像修士一般
you are a man of monkish virtue.
我根本抓不住你的把柄
You have no vices to expose.
所以对你进行暴力威胁
So threats of personal violence
只会坚定你的决心  对吧
will only harden your resolve, huh?
不  那个
No, that...
别啊  先生  不必谦虚
Come, sir, don't be modest.
你这样的人很稀有
You... are a rare animal.
不过这也让我们进入了两难境地
But... that does lead us to this sad pickle.
既然我没法说服你服从我
Since I can't persuade you to do as I ask,
那么唯一可行的办法就是杀了你
the only rational option is to kill you
然后和你的继任者谈判
and negotiate with whomever replaces you as commissioner.
现在吗  老大
Now, chief?
别急啊  维克多
One moment, Victor.
局长大人总得考虑考虑吧
The commissioner deserves time to process all this...
或者祈祷一下什么的
say a prayer or what have you.
你想要我做什么
What do you want me to do?
没必要说了
It's not worth talking about.
反正你不会同意的
You wouldn't do it.
说说看
Tell me.
我需要我的朋友吉姆·戈登恢复警探职位
I need my friend Jim Gordon reinstated as a detective.
瞧见没  你不乐意
See? You hate that idea.
不  我  我同意
No, I'll... I'll do it.
别  我看得出你不是真心
Mm-mm, I can tell that you're not sincere.
即便你今天听了我的  回头不知道哪天
Even if you do as I ask, someday, down the line,
你又会改变心意  和他对着干了
you'll change your mind, and you'll turn on him again.
现在该杀他了吧
Want me to kill him now?
不  给他做一份奶酪面包
No, make him a nice cheese toastie.
废话  现在就杀了他
Yes, kill him now, please.
就是确认一下
Just wanted to be clear.
不  等等  我们再谈谈
No, wait! Let's talk about this.
抱歉  我也是没有办法了
Sorry. Least worst option.
当然了  除非你
Unless, of course... uh...
不  你不可能同意的
No, you would never agree.
什么  同意什么
To what? Agree to what?!
*再见  别过*
*So long, farewell*
*再会  再见了*
*Auf Wiedersehen, good-bye*
*再见*
*Good-bye*
很好  很好  非常好听
Lovely, lovely, bravo.
非常遗憾  詹姆斯市长今天不能来了
Mayor James regrets he's unable to attend today,
但他委托了一位挚友代他出席
but he's sent a dear friend in his stead.
掌声有请广受尊敬的商人
Please welcome distinguished businessman,
富有远见的科学家  知名慈善家
visionary scientist, acclaimed philanthropist
同时也是哥谭商会
and new chairman of development
新任发展部主席  西奥·盖勒文先生
at the Gotham Chamber of Commerce, Mr. Theo Galavan.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
今天非常荣幸来到这里
What an honor it is to be here today,
来为一位优秀的人
to help bid farewell to a great man
本市的忠诚公仆主持卸任典礼
and a faithful servant of this city.
对于基里安·洛布  我能说什么呢
What can I say about Gillian Loeb?
谁讲个笑话解解闷
Someone tell me a funny story.
我有个好笑的
I have a good one.
我上大学的时候
So when I was in college,
我加入了校马球队
I played for the varsity polo team
我有  一大群马驹
and I had a... a string of ponies.
各位
Greetings!
我是扎丹  灵魂收割者
I am Zaardon, the Soul Reaper.
话说我有好几匹马
So I had these ponies...
我是这座城市的新来者
I'm an adopted son of this city.
我在哥谭还没住多久
I haven't lived in Gotham very long,
但我已经像本地人那样爱她了
but I already love her like a native.
这座城市
It just...
就是有种吸引力  对不对
it just kind of grabs hold of you, doesn't it?
这里有魔法
There's magic here.
魔法
Magic.
这都得归功于像基里安·洛布
And that is down to everyday heroes
这样的全职英雄
like Gillian Loeb.
局长先生  感谢你多年的贡献
Mr. Commissioner, thank you for your service.
谢谢大家
Thank you very much, everybody.
我衷心祝愿
My best wishes to...
艾森局长  工作顺利
Commissioner Essen.
宿管就说了  "你不能把他们带进来"
And the maitre d' says, "You can't bring them in here."
听好了  奴才们  我的耐心就要耗尽
Hear me, slaves. My patience is wearing thin.
不想被收魂  就跪地求饶吧
Surrender your souls to my mercy,
否则我以主人发誓
or I swear by the master,
我定要饱餐你们的痛苦
I shall feast on your pain.
酷刑折磨你们来取乐
I shall gorge on your torment.
像踩死臭虫一般碾压你们
I shall crush you like a bug.
第五区请求支援  第五区
Backup to area five! Area five!
欢迎回来  吉姆
Welcome back, Jim.
我不知道你是怎么办到的
I don't know how you pulled this off,
但我很高兴你办到了
but I'm glad you did.
他向来很有办法
He's a resourceful man.
恭喜你们了
Congratulations, to both of you.
谢谢  这是一个新起点  吉姆
Thank you. And it is a new day, Jim.
我们一定要干一番大事
We're going to do great things.
那是当然
Yes, we are.
新时期开始了
It is a new day.
一切都会好的  我保证
Things are gonna be all right. I promise.
希望这是值得的
I hope it was worth it.
我也希望如此
I hope so, too.
吉姆
Jim...
怎么了
What's wrong?
阿卡姆精神病院出事了
There's been an incident. At Arkham Asylum.
六名病人越狱了
Six inmates have escaped.
芭芭拉·基恩也在其中
Barbara Kean was one of them.
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
这是什么鬼地方
What the hell is this place?
反正不是阿卡姆
Ain't Arkham, anyhow.
情况有改观
Things are looking up.
欢迎各位
Welcome, everyone.
我是西奥·盖勒文  这是我妹妹塔比莎
My name is Theo Galavan. This is my sister Tabitha.
我的天  真辣啊
Oh, my God, look at that.
我早晚有一天得把上她
Yeah, I got to get my hands on that.
我能理解
I understand.
你们会感到不解  恐惧
You're feeling confused, scared...
还有点犯晕  不过请不要紧张
a little groggy... but please, relax.
今天  你们迎来了美好未来
Today is the first day of a wonderful future for all of you.
如果你们想的话
If you want it.
你是谁
Who are you?
现在该问的是  你们是谁
Well, now, the question is who are you?
世人视你们为精神病罪犯
The world sees criminal lunatics.
我看到的却是天才
I see brilliance.
是魅力
I see charisma.
是力量
And power.
我看到了力量
I see power.
没错
Yes.
太对了哥们  你说巧不巧
Exactly, my man. Oh, that is so spooky.
我就是这样
That is me to a T.
其他这些白痴我不好说  但是
These other bozos, oh, I don't know, but...
你说到我心里去了
You're singing my song.
闭嘴  杰罗姆
Quiet, Jerome.
你继续
Keep talking.
想象一下  你们这样一群
Imagine a group of brilliant outlaws
天才罪犯
like yourselves,
每个人都有独门绝技
each selected for their unique ability,
集结在一起团队合作
all working together as a team.
想象一下那种协同效应
Imagine the synergy.
想象一下那种威力
Imagine the impact.
哥谭会在你们面前颤抖
Gotham would tremble before you.
你说得真好听
Well, that sounds fabulous,
不过我可不是什么天才犯罪
but I am not a brilliant outlaw.
我只是有些...
I just have...
问题
issues.
你有残忍
You have ferocity
美丽  和欲望  这就够了
and beauty and desire and that's enough.
加入我吧  芭芭拉
Come with me, Barbara.
不管你想要什么东西
Whatever you want in the world,
我都给你
it's yours.
西奥
Theo?
你是叫西奥吧
That's your name, right... Theo?
你未免太心急了点
You're getting way ahead of yourself, here.
首先  别对她动手动脚的
First of all, keep your hands off her.
其次  你这套"魔力小队"的说辞
Second, this whole "Magic team"?
我没兴趣  我不喜欢听人调遣
I gotta pass. I don't take orders.
不过还是祝你顺利了  这主意挺有趣
Good luck on everything, though. It's an intriguing concept.
我非常失望
This is very disappointing.
还得礼尚往来
Fair play.
你把我们救出阿卡姆  所以想要报酬
You want a reward for busting us out of Arkham.
我很感激你  给你一百万怎么样
I am grateful. How's a million bucks sound?
够可以了吧
Pretty good, huh?
等我一重获自由
I can get it for you today,
今天就能拿给你
as soon as I hit the street.
我要的不是钱
Money's not the concern.
我本对你寄予厚望
I had such high hopes for you.
没想到你会争风吃醋
I didn't anticipate sexual jealousy.
这总会坏大事
That always poisons the well.
不能留你了
You have to go.
塔比莎会送你上路的
Tabitha will see you out.
基恩小姐得跟我走
Miss Kean is coming with me.
她可不会想和你作伴
Oh, she doesn't want to go where you're going.
还有谁想走
Anyone else want to leave?
我问你
Now...
你完全确定要这么做吗  布鲁斯少爷
you're absolutely sure about this, Master Bruce?
-我强烈建议...  -阿尔弗雷德
- I strongly advise... - Alfred.
我必须得知道
I need to know.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
好吧  少爷
Right, sir.
-太好了  炸开了  -太好了
- Yes, we're in! - Yes, yes!
布鲁斯
"亲爱的布鲁斯
"Dear Bruce,
这几周来我感觉处境危险
"These last weeks I begin to feel very mortal,
所以给你写了这封信
"which prompts this note to you.
也许是我多虑了
"Perhaps I'm being paranoid.
但愿如此
"I hope so.
无论如何  如果你在读这封信
"In any case, if you're reading this,
那我已经死了
"then I'm dead,
而你也猜出了开门密码就是'布鲁斯'
"And you figured out that the entry code is... BRUCE.
非常抱歉
"I'm sorry
我不得不把我的这一面藏起来
"I had to hide this part of my life from you,
因为这个地方就是因你才存在
"because this place only exists because of you.
成为父亲  让我想做更好的人
"Becoming a father made me want to be a better man,
而我也开始对家族生意
"and I started asking hard questions
提出尖锐的问题
"about the family business.
所以才到了今天这步
"So here we are.
我写这封信的时候  你只有12岁
"As I write this, you're 12,
是个心地善良的好孩子
"and a fine, good-hearted boy.
所以我肯定  你会成长为善良的好人
"So I'm sure you'll be a fine, good-hearted man.
但我也只知道这些了
"But that's all I know.
我不知道我和你母亲出了什么事
"I don't know what happened to me or your mother,
也不知道你这些年过得如何
"or how life has turned out for you.
更不知道你多大了
"I don't even know how old you are.
所以我就不给你什么父亲的忠告了
"So I'll resist giving you much fatherly advice.
只能告诉你
"Only this:
幸福和真相
"You can't have both happiness
不可兼得
"and the truth.
你必须做出选择
"You have to choose.
求求你  我的儿子
"I beg of you, my son,
一定要选择幸福
please choose happiness.
除非
"Unless...
除非你找到了自己的使命
"Unless you feel a calling.
真正的使命"
A true calling."